Why are you here for performance? I
could be the most relevant person at
this conference. I secretly think you're
a Bitcoiner. I ask the people to look
around this conference. I've never been
to a conference this big. You know,
30,000 people who are here who are
completely confident that they can't
lose and Bitcoin's got no place to go
but up. To ask themselves, okay, here I
am at this huge conference with this
massive exhibit hall with all this money
being spent on all these high-tech
booths. Do I think I'm early or am I
late? This might be the peak of the
mania. And you know, we've got the
government in here. We got vice
president was here. You know, Donald
Trump as a candidate spoke at the
conference last year, but now we got all
these senators and we got state uh
governments buying Bitcoin, the
government buying Bitcoin. To me, it
seems like that's the end of it. Only 5%
of the world owns Bitcoin. Isn't that
pretty ugly? That's a lot. Everybody in
the world has heard gold is gold. The
last thing we need is a Bitcoin
standard. But we should go back to a
gold standard, but not a Bitcoin
standard because Bitcoin is nothing.
This bracelet here is probably about
$20,000 worth of gold. It's melted down.
But what about the Bitcoin here? Now the
government is going to take my money and
buy Bitcoin. They said they won't. Well,
if you price Bitcoin in gold, despite
all the hype and all the, you know, the
political backing and all the NFTts and
the strategic reserves and all this,
Bitcoin today as we're at this
conference is about 10% lower than it
was in at its peak in 2021 priced in
gold. People are saying, "How can all
30,000 of us are right and you're wrong,
right?" Well, because it's a Bitcoin
conference, right? I mean, if it was an
idiot conference, right? Yes. All the
idiots would be wrong. The Chinese are
smart. The Americans are they also
[Music]
we're at the Bitcoin Las Vegas
conference and joining us right now is
somebody who you may not expect to be at
a premier Bitcoin conference. Someone
who has been very critical of the entire
Bitcoin space for a very long time and
still is. uh Peter Schiff, chairman of
uh Europacific uh CIO rather of Europe
Pacific Asset Management and uh the
president of Shift Gold. Peter, I'm
joined by my co-host, Bonnie Chang.
Welcome to the show. Thanks for having
me here. Uh well, just to follow up on
my introduction, you tweeted this. I'm
going to show you and the audience just
a few seconds of you tweeting this from
your booth. I'm here at this exhibit
hall from the Bitcoin conference setting
up the Europeacific Asset Management
booth. But it really is amazing the the
size of this uh exhibit hall and all of
the companies that are exhibiting really
high tech stuff, very expensive booths.
It's a massive conference. I mean, this
is way bigger, I think, than the
mortgage bankers conference I came to in
uh in 2006 here in Vegas as far as the
amount of money that's that's being
spent by the exhibitors. They have much
fancier booths. I remember I was
laughing at all the uh the booths at the
uh mortgage conference. They had like
sub subprime, you know, we'll we'll
finance anybody, you know, even if you
just got out of prison, no problem.
we'll get you nothing down, no doc
mortgage, you know, and that was really
the peak of the
insanity. And you know, this is
certainly like peak insanity here. And
this is before anybody even arrives. But
it's just amazing what a complete waste
of money and resources, everything.
Nothing. All of this being spent on
companies that produce nothing, uh,
provide no real value and just allow
people to gamble on Bitcoin and other
cryptocurrencies. I mean, obviously, it
makes sense that this conference is
taking place in Las Vegas. In fact, they
ought to have, you know, in the, you
know, casinos where they have blackjack
and roulette and, you know, craps, they
ought to have little tables where you
can trade Bitcoin. You know, at least
you could get drinks served to you by
pretty girls. It might be a a better way
to gamble. Anyway, that's it for now
everybody. Bye-bye. All right. So, and
then the entire You went on to say the
entire industry is insane. There's just
so much money being spent here. It's
crazy. It's a big bubble. You've
compared it to the mortgage uh uh
conference uh that you attended in 2006,
right before the mortgage, you know, NBS
security crash in 2008. Is that what's
happening right now? Why are you here
first and foremost? Well, you know, a
lot of people ask me that question as
they're asking me to pose for a selfie
with them, but um you know, I I know
from experience because almost everybody
that comes up to me says the same thing.
You're the reason I own Bitcoin. And now
that was not my intention, right? I'm
not proud of the fact that I've
converted more people to Bitcoin than
any other human being alive, but the
reality is I have. Uh, and you know, so
I'm, you know, I'm the big Bitcoiner
because I am the one that really got
people to Bitcoin mainly because I got
them to understand um, economics,
Austrian economics, sound money, gold,
and they they just went, you know, a bit
too far and and and and went past where
I brought them and ended up at Bitcoin.
Now, you know, they've made money. I
mean by act, you know, that wasn't, you
know, my intention, but they ended up
buying Bitcoin. And if they sold it
today, they'd obviously make a lot of
money. The problem is they're not
selling, they're buying more. And every
time I tell people not to buy Bitcoin,
they they go and buy more Bitcoin. And
uh so I, you know, I've got this
unintended consequence like like a
government program, right? It it does
the opposite of what what I intend. Uh,
but I think, you know, I I'm people who
are in Bitcoin, they know me. You know,
either they they got into it because of
me or they just read my stuff or they
they know that I'm anti- Bitcoin. Um,
but so, you know, I could be the most
relevant person at this conference to to
Bitcoin because every everybody else is
just an echo chamber. Everybody else
just says, "Yeah, Bitcoin's great.
Bitcoin's going to the moon." I mean,
who the hell needs to come to a
conference to hear that? It's more like
just a giant party, right, for people to
just celebrate.
Um, you know, how much money they have.
But, you know, I asked people when I did
my my panel today because I think, you
know, just based on the greater fool
theory and people buy Bitcoin because
they expect to sell it at a higher price
and the people who buy it from them have
the same expectation uh to be able to
sell it at a higher price. And so like
all pyramids or Ponzi schemes, you know,
the people who get in early make a lot
of money, but they make a lot of money
because the people who come in late lose
that money and it's just a transfer. So
I asked the people to look around this
conference. I've never been to a
conference this big. you know, 30,000
people who are here who are completely
confident that they can't lose and
Bitcoin's got no place to go but up to
ask themselves, okay, here I am at this
huge conference with this massive
exhibit hall with all this money being
spent on all these high-tech booths. Do
I think I'm early or am I late?
Because to me, nobody at this conference
who's buying Bitcoin is getting in
early. Now, you know, is this conference
going to get to 50,000, 100,000? I mean,
how many people are theoretically going
to be at a at a crypto conference? This
might be the peak uh of the mania. And,
you know, we've got the government in
here. We got the vice president was
here.
Um, you know, Donald Trump as a
candidate spoke at the conference last
year, but now we got all these senators
and we got state uh governments buying
Bitcoin, the government buying Bitcoin.
You know, to me it seems like that's the
end of it. You know, you've got
corporations that got in, government got
in. But, you know, why are the
governments in? They're in because
they've been bought and paid for uh by
the special interests. the politicians
are seeking votes and they're seeking c
campaign donations and so they're
pandering to the Bitcoin special
interest which is now large enough to
bribe these politicians but again that's
more of an indication that you know this
is a peak rather than you know the
ground floor of something uh we're near
near the end of something. Um Michael
Turpin was here he's the Bitcoin OG and
he said only 5% of the world owns
Bitcoin. Isn't that pretty early? That's
a lot. That is a lot of people. You get
5% of the people to own anything. I
mean, first of all, I mean, how many
people are in Africa, right? I mean,
how, you know, I mean, there's a lot of
people that are just not going to own
it, right? I mean, you know, uh, and you
know, how many, look, there's what, how
many, how many people are in China? A
billion and a half, a billion eight
billion people in India. You really
think all those people are going to own
Bitcoin? I mean, half the people who own
Bitcoin live in America. What does that
tell you? Right? There's a lot of
Americans who own Bitcoin. And why do
they own Bitcoin? Do they do they need
it? Do they use it as a medium of
exchange? No. They're just gambling with
it. They're buying it because they think
they're going to get rich. You're you're
never going to have 100% market
penetration, right? But pretty much
everybody knows about Bitcoin. I mean,
even the people who don't own it know
about it, right? When I first learned
about it, hardly anybody knew about it,
right? So, I guess at that point it was
early. I just didn't believe it could
ever become what it's became. Uh but
yeah, when I first heard about it,
hardly anybody knew what it was. So that
was early. But now there's hardly
anybody who doesn't know what Bitcoin
is. Uh and the fact that there are a lot
of people that don't own Bitcoin,
despite knowing about it, that tells you
that they they just they haven't they
don't believe in it. I mean, why would
somebody who knows about Bitcoin and who
has chosen not to buy it over the last
few years, why would they decide to buy
it a year from now, two years from now?
I mean, they they didn't want to buy it
today. What's going to change? I mean,
the only thing that could change is the
price. Maybe the price will go up, but
maybe it'll go down. So, I think we have
pretty deep penetration into the market.
Um, can it go to 6% of the world? I bet
I guess you know I mean but you know
maybe maybe this is the peak uh or close
enough to it because if you look at
Bitcoin's peak price in 2021 right and I
you know I think peaks are significant
so look at the the last peak from that
period
uh the price of Bitcoin was about 69,000
at that peak almost
70,000 and now it's you know north of
100,000 about 108,000 something like
that
But if you price Bitcoin in gold, which
is probably the fairest way to price it
rather than any fiat currencies,
especially if they claim that it's
digital gold, right? So they're trying
to compare Bitcoin to gold. They they
make it look like gold when they depict
it. It's a coin with a golden color. But
if you price Bitcoin in
gold, despite all the hype, right, all
the, you know, the political backing and
all the NFTTS and the strategic reserves
and all this, Bitcoin today as we're at
this conference is about 10% lower than
it was in at its peak in 2021 priced in
gold. So why is that? Why why hasn't it
gone up? So maybe it's peaked. Maybe it
peaked in 2021 and we kind of double
topped around now and the next big move
is is down.
But everybody else, everybody in the
world has heard gold. Does that mean
gold peaked? No, because gold's not a
mania. Gold's not a a bubble. Gold's
just been around for thousands of
years. And um you know, gold, you know,
gold is gold. Gold doesn't really
change. What changes is the value of
fiat currencies. How much you know of a
currency do you need to buy gold? And
when we had a you know a stable monetary
system that was you know there was no
central bank what we were on you know
gold was our money. Uh the price was
constant. You know the first coinage act
in 1789 defined a dollar as a weight of
gold and basically um 20 an ounce of
gold was $20. That's what it was. Uh
$20, you know, was 1 ounce. And when we
created the Federal Reserve in
1913, it was still $20 an ounce. And it
stayed 20 until 1933 when Roosevelt
devalued. And now you needed $35 to buy
an ounce of gold. So the dollar was now
worth less gold than it was before
Roosevelt devalued. And it stayed $35 an
ounce until Richard Nixon was president.
and he devalued the dollar a couple of
times and he left it at $42 and like 22
or something like that. And then we
said, "Okay, forget it. We're off. You
know, the dollar is no is no longer
defined by gold. The dollar is not worth
its weight in gold. It's it's just worth
whatever somebody will will, you know,
pay for it. That's it's just free
floating fiat currency. No longer has
any uh, you know, tangible backing to
it. And ever since then, you've need
more more and more dollars to buy an
ounce of gold. Now you need, you know,
$3,300 to buy an ounce of gold. But gold
hasn't changed. It's the same ounce of
gold. Uh what's changed is the
purchasing power of the dollar, fiat
fiat, uh Federal Reserve note. And
that's going to continue. I mean, we
have massive deficits that are only
going to get bigger, not smaller. you
know, for all the political hype of
Doge, uh, you know, the Republican big
beautiful bill takes a debt problem and
makes it worse. The deficits that were
already big will be bigger as a result
of this bill than they would have been
had they never passed it. Why? Well,
because they have tax cuts and spending
increases beyond what was already
scheduled. and and so there's bigger
deficits, so there's more money
printing, and so dollars are going to
lose value, and you're going to need
more dollars to buy the ounce of gold.
But I'd say that the entire move
probably over the last year and a half
where gold's gone from about 2,000 to,
you know, 3,300, 50% increase in the
price of gold has happened with very
little public interest. The public has
not been buying gold. They've been
buying Bitcoin instead of gold. The
buyers have been mainly central banks,
foreign central banks, who I think are a
lot more sophisticated than the typical
Bitcoin buyer. And I think that they're
buying gold because they're selling
dollars. And they're looking for a
diversification from their
reserves. And I think they recognize
that the dollar's value is going to
decline. that its days as the reserve
currency are o are you know numbered not
they're not over yet but they're coming
to an end and so they're preva preparing
for a world where the dollar is no
longer you know the the you know the
center of uh global monetary system and
so if you're going to replace your
dollars what are you going to replace it
with you going to buy euros you're going
to buy yen you're going to buy pounds I
mean all those currencies have their own
issues I think the most likely
alternative for central banks to hold is
gold. And so they've been buying and I
think they're going to continue to buy
uh regardless of price. Uh but at some
point I think the public is going to
wake up to what the central banks are
doing and and join in and uh and so
that's going to send the gold price up
even higher when now you have, you know,
private investors both retail and
institutional competing with central
banks to buy uh a scarce quantity of
gold. And eventually, I think a lot of
the people at this Bitcoin conference uh
will be trying to buy gold, too. And
maybe they'll be trying to cash in their
Bitcoin uh to buy gold. But, you know,
when a significant number of people want
to sell their Bitcoin, the problem is
there's nobody to buy it. Is that why
you're here to convert the Bitcoiners
into the gold people? Well, I'm hoping
to talk some sense into these people.
But the problem is we're in this echo
chamber, right? You know, that people
are saying, "How can all 30,000 of us
are right and you're wrong, right?"
Right. Well, because it's a Bitcoin
conference, right? I mean, if it was an
idiot conference, right? Yes. All the
idiots would be wrong. And if I showed
up at an idiot conference, not being an
idiot myself, right? So, it's it's it
it's not a random sample of people that
are happen to be at this Bitcoin
conference. I'm the only one here that
doesn't like Bitcoin. What led us up to
now? I mean, you brought up the gold
standard. Okay. Why do you think Nixon
took the dollar off the gold standard?
There's different theories. What's your
take? Well, the alternative, I guess,
was political suicide. I mean, the
problem was the government mainly under,
you know, prior to Nixon coming on
board, a lot a lot of it was under Linda
Lyndon Johnson. Uh, but during the
1960s, you had, you know, the war on
poverty, Great Society, Vietnam, uh, the
you know, the moon mission. So, we spent
a lot of money. Um, and we issued a lot
of debt. We didn't have gold to back it
up, right? And, and so, we came to an
inflection point where either we needed
to deflate,
uh, devalue or
default. And so in order to devalue
uh or deflate rather the bubble uh we
would have had to have prices coming way
down
uh to meet the gold price.
Alternatively, we could massively
devalue the dollar and and make gold,
you know, that Nixon tried devaluation,
but it wasn't enough because he only
devalued a little bit. Uh but it would
have been very politically embar
embarrassing to substantially devalue
the dollar. Uh so they basically chose
defaulting on the obligations. Remember
um Federal Reserve notes for obligations
to pay gold that we did not have, right?
Because we created too many notes. It's
like if you have a checking account and
you write a bunch of checks but that
exceed your balance, right? You you know
these checks are going to bounce if any
people try to cash them. And we had
issued a lot more Federal Reserve notes
than we had dollars to back them up
because the Federal Reserve notes were
IUS for for for gold, right? That you
know, people were loaning us uh their
gold and and so rather than massive cuts
to government spending that would have
been required, deflation of prices
coming down uh and defaults and and and
bankruptcies. A lot of things would have
had to happen. Nixon took the easy way
out. And you know, we did have a big
inflation that followed anyway. We had a
lot of inflation. That's why we had the
price increases of the 1970s. Uh because
Nixon, you know, made the choice that he
did. And if you remember, you know, or
know about the 1970s, the dollar lost
about twothirds of its value versus the
Deutsch mark, the yen, the Swiss Frank.
But it lost even more relative to gold,
right? It went from $35 an ounce to
$850. But oil prices went from $3 a
barrel to $30 a barrel. It's a 10-fold
increase. But oil prices didn't really
go up. The dollar went down. You know,
when when we were giving OPEC $3 to buy
a barrel of oil, we were giving them $3
that were backed by gold that were
redeemable in gold. But when we were
giving them $30, we were just giving
them paper. They couldn't get anything.
Uh so it was politically expedient for
Richard Nixon to take that path. And
unfortunately that path became available
to him uh in the Johnson administration
because that's where they allowed the
president was given the authority to do
that under Johnson. And in fact my
father is one of the few people who
testified in front of the Senate Banking
Committee Committee against that. But
you know the chairman of the Federal
Reserve at the time the uh the president
secretary of the treasury they were all
in favor of this. And my father said
that if we go off the gold standard,
it's going to lead to higher inflation,
right? Gold prices are going to go up.
And the the Federal Reserve chairman and
the Secretary of Treasury said the
opposite. They said that it was the
dollar that was propping up gold. And if
we went off the gold standard, the gold
price would fall, that it was the dollar
that was supporting gold, and that we
would actually have lower inflation
going off the gold standard. So, you
know, everything that the Federal
Reserve chairman and the Treasury
Secretary chairman said would happen was
wrong. And my my dad got everything
right. So, why not put the dollar back
on a commodity- based system, a Bitcoin
standard today? Bitcoin's capped unlike
gold, by the way. So, you know, the idea
of a Bitcoin standard
evaluate is a Bitcoin standard, but we
we we should go back to a gold standard,
but the reason why not a Bitcoin
standard because Bitcoin is nothing. I
mean, you
know, you can't back you can't back
nothing with nothing. You have to back
nothing with something. But there's a
cap. I don't care. There's a there's a
limited supply of nothing. But but also
people focus on the 21 million number.
What about the 2.1 quadrillion number?
That's how many Satoshi's there are.
Because one Bitcoin is just an arbitrary
bundle of a 100 million
Satoshi's. So there's there's so many
Satoshi's out there. There's there's
enough for every man, woman, and child
on the planet to have hundreds of
thousands of these things. But you can't
do anything with a Satoshi just like you
can't do anything with a 100 million
Satoshi's. All you can do is give them
to somebody else. But there's no real
value there. It's not like an ounce of
gold that has value because you can make
stuff with it. You can do things with
it. But the reason that politicians
don't want to go back on a gold standard
is for the same reason they went off it.
Gold provides discipline to politicians.
When you're on a gold standard, you
can't promise something for nothing. You
can't run two $3 trillion a year
deficits. You can't vote for tax cuts
and lie to your constituents that you
cut your taxes, right? Uh you you need
to be honest. You know, gold is like a a
chapron at at at at the political prong.
And the politicians don't want the
chaperone. They don't want to act
responsibly. They don't want to tell
their voters they can't have this and
they can't have that. we got to cut this
and we got to cut that. Uh, you know,
and the people at the conference, you
know, Bitcoin people, they always think,
oh, the gold standard failed and that
that's so gold doesn't work. The gold
standard didn't fail. It worked
perfectly. We failed as people to stay
on the gold standard. We went off it uh
when it became tough to stay on it. And
that's not gold's fault. Had we, you
know, respected the gold standard, we
would not be in the financial mess that
we're in now. And just because you know
politicians had no stomach for gold
standard doesn't mean that they would
have stomach for a Bitcoin standard e
either even if you you could implement
one. People think oh we're going to go
we're going to use Bitcoin because gold
didn't work. Gold worked perfectly.
That's why we got rid of it because it
was doing exactly what it was supposed
to do. And so the same politicians who
don't want a gold standard aren't going
to want a Bitcoin standard. The reason
you have politicians today that are
advocating for Bitcoin is because
they've been bought and paid for by the
Bitcoin special interest groups. Bitcoin
is now a large enough group that it has
political muscle. The biggest donors in
the last campaign cycle was crypto more
than the defense, more than the
pharmaceutical companies. They bought
political influence. And so now you have
politicians who are pandering to that
interest group because they want their
money and they want their votes. And so
it's now the most corrupt part I think
of the American political system. The
fact that politicians are selling out
their country for the select interest of
a group of Bitcoin holders uh who you
know want to make money off the
government pumping up um their their
tokens so they can sell their tokens to
the public.
And the public has no say in the matter.
I mean, I I don't want to buy Bitcoin.
I've never bought Bitcoin. I mean, um,
but now the government is going to take
my money and buy Bitcoin. They said they
won't. Well, if you look at the Lumis
bill,
right? Where is the money going to come
from? Well, they want to take the money
that they get from the Federal Reserve
every year and use that to buy Bitcoin.
Well, but you know, they should use that
to pay down the debt. That's not free.
We're going to take money that we would
have got and we're going to use it to
buy Bitcoin. But the other thing that
Lumis wants us to do is she wants to uh
mark to market the US government's gold
holdings because it's still on the books
at the $42, you know, where Nixon left
it and wants to, you know, revalue it to
three 3,000 an ounce, $3,300, which of
course, you know, makes no difference
because nobody believes it's worth 42
$42. But what she then wants is the
Federal Reserve to take that new
valuation, which would be, you know,
hundreds of billions of dollars, and
print new money, say, "Oh, because the
US government has all this gold, we're
going to print all this money and loan
it to the Treasury, collateralized by
this gold, and now she wants to take
those newly printed dollars, hundreds of
billions of dollars, and buy Bitcoin
with them." Now, that's not costless.
That's massive inflation. you are
inflating the money supply to buy
Bitcoin and all the people that sell the
government their Bitcoin are now going
to take that money and go shopping and
so bid up prices and so the people who
didn't have Bitcoin to sell to the
government are now losers because now
everything they want to buy is more
expensive because all the people who had
Bitcoin got all this extra cash from the
government. So creating inflation to buy
Bitcoin is it costless to the public?
There is a huge inflationary tax.
exacted from the public, but the winners
are the Bitcoin lobby that now gets to
sell their Bitcoin to the government
strategic reserve, but the country uh
loses. And meanwhile, you know, all of
the money now that has been misdirected
to Bitcoin. Look at all these companies
now that are being formed, Bitcoin
treasury companies, right? What do these
companies do? They buy Bitcoin. What
value does that add to the US economy?
Nothing. you know, no goods are produc
produced, no services are provided. They
just raise all this money and go out and
buy Bitcoin with it and then they borrow
money and buy more Bitcoin and they
issue stock and buy Bitcoin, right? This
is all a big uh, you know, pyramid of a
Ponzi. Uh, and and and meanwhile, you
know, the Chinese are building factories
and making stuff, you know, and Trump
says he wants us to be more
self-reliant. He wants us to produce
more. Well, how are we going to produce
more stuff if we're creating meme coins,
right? Uh so the government is is
misallocating and misdirecting resources
and capital where it shouldn't be
because if it wasn't for all this
government crypto support, this wouldn't
be happening. Can we say we like gold,
but it's just a new generation prefers
Bitcoin? We It's not a either gold or
Bitcoin type of debate. It could be, I
like gold, but we prefer Bitcoin. Yeah.
They just they prefer it because they
don't really understand it. I mean,
people are young. And when you're young,
you know, you're very
idealistic. You you don't have the
wisdom that comes uh with age. And so, a
lot of people think young people think
they know a lot more than their parents
and their and their grandparents. But,
you know, I think that there is a a a
sexy story to
Bitcoin and the fact that, you know,
there is all this technology behind it
uh that's appealing to people. But I
think the main appeal is the get-rich
quick scheme. I think people are
interested in Bitcoin because they've
been told that they're going to get rich
if they buy it. And if they don't buy
it, they're going to be poor. That is
the that is the selling point. the FOMO.
You have to buy this. It's almost like,
you know, with college degrees. So many
Americans were told you need to get a
college degree because if you don't,
your your life is ruined, right? They
used to say, if you don't get a college
degree, you're going to have to cook
French fries for a living. And now they
say, you know, if you want to cook
French fries, you got to go get a
college degree, right? Because
everybody's got these degrees. Because
they were they were they were scared
that if they didn't get one, you know,
their life was over. And it's kind of a
similar thing with Bitcoin, you know,
have fun staying poor if you don't buy
it. And and you can never sell your
Bitcoin. That's the other thing. Like
you you just have to buy it and pretend
you don't own it because you can't, you
know, you have to just hold it forever
and never sell it. And the people who
want you to never sell your Bitcoin are
the people who are selling you their
Bitcoin, right? You because somebody is
selling because otherwise there wouldn't
be any Bitcoin uh to buy. So I think
kids have been misled and they're, you
know, they're young, they're ignorant,
they're greedy, they're, you know,
they're easily influenced by this. But
what I think ultimately the young people
will come to realize or come to prefer
is you can have the functionality of
Bitcoin with gold except better,
cheaper, and faster because anybody can
custody gold. And if you want to
tokenize it and issue tokens that
represent ownership of that gold, you
can buy the token, which means you own
the gold, but you can transact in the
token. So I can send tokens or receive
tokens and I can buy goods and services
or get paid for providing services or
producing goods. I can be paid in gold.
I can price my products in gold and we
can transact with each other
instantaneously using our our cell
phones or text messaging and the gold
doesn't have to go anywhere. The gold
just sits in a vault and acts as a basis
for all these
transactions. Uh but now I'm using real
money and gold is a store of value but
it's also a medium of exchange and a
unit of account. Bitcoin is not a store
of value because there value to store,
but it's a lousy medium of exchange
because it's slow and expensive and it's
not a good unit of account because of
it's it's too volatile. But gold works
as money. Tokenized gold works even
better just like you know the initial uh
banks that issued paper
currency. That was to make it easier to
transact in gold because the paper
currency was backed by and redeemable in
gold. But instead of carrying my gold
around, I carried paper around. But all
those bills represented I use for gold.
My gold was safely stored in with a
blacksmith or then with a bank and they
gave me pieces of paper that represented
ownership of that gold that I could use
in commerce. Well, now we don't have to
issue paper that's backed by gold. We
can issue digital tokens. And now I can
transfer those tokens to you using the
internet and I can transfer them halfway
across the world instantly for next to
nothing. So we, you know, we we can have
digital gold, real gold digitized.
Bitcoin is not digital gold. It's
digital fool's gold. But I just feel
like whatever you described, Bitcoin can
do better because if you put gold in
vaults, then there's third party risk.
If you look at Bitcoin, there is a cap.
But gold has no cap has no cap, right?
But gold is very scarce and there's not
a lot of gold. The supply of gold grows
by maybe 1% to 2% a year, which is about
the growth of the world's population. So
gold is a very, very scarce asset. But
not only is it scarce, it's extremely
valuable because of the properties that
it has that make it unique. Bitcoin may
be scarce, you know, and if you think
about it as 21 2.1 quadrillion Satoshi's
doesn't sound that scarce, but even if
you just look at the number of Bitcoin,
right, the the the units of Satoshi's,
21 million, it could be scarce, but it
doesn't have value. It doesn't have a
use like gold does. Um, and so just
because something is scarce doesn't mean
uh it's it's it's going to be valuable.
You you have to be valuable and scarce.
And and I think Bitcoin is actually
neither because there are lots of other
tokens. There's tens of thousands of
tokens. Uh now there's all these meme
coins and in each meme coin is scarce,
right? There's a cap, right, on the
number there are, but they all compete
with one another. Gold doesn't compete
with all the other metals. I mean
sometimes you can substitute you could
use silver instead of gold or maybe
platinum or maybe you can use copper but
there's a very limited number of metals
but for certain things you know you need
gold. The other metals won't work but
there there's no limit to the number of
tokens that that we could use. You don't
have to use Bitcoin. Just because
Bitcoin was first and just because
Bitcoin is the biggest today doesn't
mean it's going to be the biggest
tomorrow. people's change and people
invent a better a better
mousetrap. Um, so and as far as
custodians, yes, you do need a custodian
with gold, but there's never going to be
a single custodian. There's multiple
custodians and they all compete with one
another for safety. You know, Brinks has
been around for about 150 years uh as a
custodian of gold. They've never lost an
ounce. Nobody who has entrusted their
gold to Brinks has ever lost any money.
Now maybe there was some robberies, but
you know what Brinkx did? They made
everybody whole because they wanted to
protect their value of their brand, of
their reputation. And in
capitalism, third parties compete for
reputation. That's why insurance works,
right? People buy life insurance, they
buy auto insurance, they buy health
insurance, they buy fire insurance. All
of that is third parties. And so you
have to trust that the third party is
going to pay your claim when you submit
one. And so it's not like third party
custodians don't work. They work very
well in a free market. And so the same
thing would be true for custodians of
gold. And the thing with Bitcoin and the
reason Bitcoin doesn't require a
custodian is because Bitcoin is nothing.
And so to custody something requires a
custodian. I don't need a custodian to
custo custody nothing. Right? But I
don't want to put my faith in nothing.
Right? Um people say, I don't want to
have to trust a custodian to hold my
gold. All right. Well, I'm only going to
use custodians that I trust, and I'm not
going to just use one custodian. I'm
going to spread my gold around. So, if
one guy screws me, somebody else won't.
And in fact, I'm going to self custody
some of my gold, right? Keep it keep it
myself. But with Bitcoin, you could say,
"Okay, I don't I I don't want to trust a
custodian." But what are you trusting? I
am trusting that the public continues to
ascribe value to nothing. Right? You
have to trust that this mass delusion
continues and that people are going to
want your Bitcoin. What if they don't
want it anymore? Right? And and it's not
like people haven't had their Bitcoin
stolen or lost. I mean, the minute you
put your Bitcoin on an exchange, right,
it could be hacked. It could be stolen.
Uh there's all kinds of scams people
have lost. I had some Bitcoin that I
lost, right? I didn't buy it. I got it
for free, but I didn't have my my
passport. And then, you know, that was
it. By the way, you put your address on
Twitter. How many people actually gave
donated to that address?
Oh, that's a new address. So, what I did
there? So the initial idea that Trump
floated for the strategic reserve was
that if he can get Bitcoin in a net
revenue neutral way that had no cost to
the taxpayer, they would get it. And so
I thought that was funny that people
were celebrating this because it was
really a hollow victory at the time. And
I said, "Okay, I'm going to do the same
thing. I'm going to establish my Bitcoin
strategic reserve. I'm going to model it
on the governments and that if I can
accumulate Bitcoin at no cost to myself,
then I'm willing to do it, right? And so
I didn't know how do I how do I get
Bitcoin without any cost? Well, people
have to give it to me. So I gave people
my address and I said, "This is my
strategic reserve. You want to help me
fund it?" And I got some Bitcoin, not a
lot, you know, but initially people
thought that I was taking it because
they saw the Bitcoin go in and then it
went out. And that's because I had an
exchange rack wallet on Coinbase. So
then I opened up a hard wallet and I
moved all that Bitcoin from the exchange
wallet to a hard wallet and and now I
put that address. That way people can
see it at all times. And so anybody that
wants to look up my the address can look
it up and they can see that the Bitcoin
is there. I see. And I've told people
that if you do put Bitcoin into my
strategic reserve, I am not going to use
it. I'm going to leave it there until
it's worthless. But, you know, I'm going
to be I'm going to be a a good Bitcoin
hodler and never sell. And I'm going to
hold to zero. But but I I also want to
use my Bitcoin reserve as an example of
why you shouldn't have a Bitcoin
reserve. But so far it hasn't worked
because it's gone up because my bit most
of the Bitcoin I think was put in there,
you know, 90,000 is and so now it's, you
know, over 100,000. I secretly think
you're a Bitcoiner.
Well, I was a Bitcoiner before other
people knew what Bitcoin was, but only
because they've, you know, redefined a
Bitcoiner to being like a gold bug,
right? But, you know, like explain that
explain that difference. Well, look,
when I was on my panel today with
Natalie Bernell and she said, "Hey, we
all believe in sound money." And the
first thing I said is, "Well, some of us
believe in sound money and some of us
think they believe in sound money." Uh
because people now ascribe all of the
characteristics to gold to Bitcoin and
they say Bitcoin is actually better than
gold. It's gold 2.0. So a lot of the
people that buy Bitcoin today are buying
Bitcoin for the reasons that I bought
gold and for the reasons that I still
buy gold and that I recommend that other
people buy gold. But I think that
they're wrong to think that Bitcoin is
digital gold. And the market will tell
you that that's not the case. If you
look at the way Bitcoin and gold trade,
they tend to trade in opposite
directions. The correlation between
Bitcoin and gold is negative. Now, over
a longer period of time, yes, Bitcoin
has been going up and gold has been
going up, but so have stocks and so have
a lot of things. But if you look at the
shortterm correlation, like daytoday,
right? If gold is up, chances are
Bitcoin is down. And if Bitcoin is down,
chances are gold is up. Bitcoin trades
uh with a high correlation with risk
assets like tech stocks and the NASDAQ.
So when the NASDAQ is up big, Bitcoin is
usually up big. The NASDAQ is down big,
Bitcoin is down big. Usually it's down
more and it's up more. Gold typically
rises when the stock market falls and
when Bitcoin falls. And when Bitcoin and
the stock market are going up, then
that's when gold is going down. So,
Bitcoin to me is the anti- gold. And so,
I don't see how it could be digital gold
when it's the opposite of gold. If it
was digital gold, it should at least be
positively correlated with gold. And in
the real world, uh, Bitcoin can't
replace gold in any any for anything. I
mean, I have a a gold watch, right? I
got a gold bracelet. I can't make this
bracelet out of Bitcoin instead of gold,
right? I can't substitute Bitcoin for
gold in consumer electronics or in
aerospace or in medicine or in dentistry
or in any one of the numerous uses. Gold
is the most useful uh metal on the
periodic table. But in no circumstance
can I choose to use Bitcoin instead of
gold because it won't work. Right? So
Bitcoin is nothing like gold in the real
world and it's nothing like gold in the
financial world. It's the opposite of
gold in the financial world. So by what
definition is it digital gold? Because
someone decided to represent it as a
coin and make it gold in color even
though it's just a string of numbers,
you know, unrelated, just random string
of numbers. Uh so I I just think it's a
Bitcoin is a collectible token that's
got nothing to do with gold. uh people
collect Bitcoin and they collect Bitcoin
for the same reason that a lot of people
collected Beanie Babies. They just they
they think that uh their collections are
going to be more valuable. They think
more people are going to want to collect
Bitcoin in the future and that their
Bitcoin collections will will go up. Uh
but I don't think it has anything in
common with gold. I mean the the story
they try to make it act like gold. You
know, you know that that's how they
represent it. They say, "Hey, it's
portable. It's divisible. It's
fungeable." Well, yes, it's all those
things and and gold is those things,
too. But just because they've replicated
some of those qualities doesn't mean
that they've turned uh Bitcoin into
gold, right? Uh you know, it it's just
fool's gold. And unfortunately, a lot of
people have bought into that that myth.
If I'm from this a country and I'm in US
now, a country is all of a sudden
someone attacks a country, I I know my
seed phrase, so I have my asset with me.
But I don't have gold or I can't carry
gold bars. Yeah. Well, I mean, first of
all, you can because you can have a lot
of value in gold. I mean, this this this
bracelet here is probably about $20,000
worth of gold. It's melted down. But
what about the Bitcoin here? What if you
forget it? I mean, you know, my memory
is starting to go. As you get older, you
can't remember. I gota I got to write my
seed phrase down. I mean, what if I lose
it? I mean like you know so you you you
you could can forget that stuff but if
you had uh you know tokenized gold right
and you you it's the same thing right
you can you you can leave and in fact
you don't even have to remember your
seed phrase because if you can let's say
I'm the custodian of your gold and you
have to rush from one country and go to
another country uh you know if you prove
to me who you are I can give you your
gold what if you are in that country
what do you mean the custo the custodian
is in that country now what Well, you
can have a custodian who's not in that
country. If you're in a country that's
really, you know, a little dicey, you'd
probably want your custodian to be
abroad, right? So, you could do that
and, you know, then your gold will be
waiting for you when when when you get
out of that oppressive country into the
into the freer country. Uh, but yes, I
mean, the idea that you can just
remember your, you know, your your seed
phrase and you don't actually need to
have anything. Yes. I mean, there's
there's some interesting in that. But
what if by the time you leave with your
seed phrase, people have decided that
they no longer value Bitcoin? And yes,
you've got your Bitcoin, but it doesn't
really have any market value anymore
because the world decided that you know
what, we were stupid to believe in this
and we don't believe in it anymore. Uh
because you know what happens with the
dynamic of any kind of pyramid or chain
letter or Ponzi? You know, you've got
all these people that are accumulating
and holding their their Bitcoin and
they're not they're not spending it,
right? And the reason they're not
spending it is because they're afraid of
missing out on on future gains. And hey,
yes, if I buy myself a car today for
$30,000 worth of
Bitcoin that could end that car could
end up costing me $3 million because the
Bitcoin I sold to buy that car would
have been worth $3 million. So, I'm not
going to buy that car. I'm going to get
by with my old car. or I'm going to use
a bicycle or whatever. But people are
holding off on cashing in their Bitcoin
because they don't they're afraid of
missing out on on the future gains. But
when we get to a point where enough
people believe that, you know what, it's
high enough. I I'm tired of waiting for
a car. I'm I'm you know, I I you know, I
I I got to get a car. This bicycle is no
good. I can't take a date out on the
backseat of my bicycle. You know, I got
to get a car. And and more of these
people decide they want to spend. Well,
now what happens? Now people are selling
their Bitcoin and so the price is going
down because if I want to buy a car, the
car dealership's not looking for
Bitcoin. They want dollars or they want
euros or, you know, pounds wherever you
happen to live. And and so now people
start selling and now the price starts
going down. And if it continues to go
down, now people are like, you know
what, I got to get rid of my Bitcoin
because if I keep holding it, it's going
to be worth less. So now the whole uh
you know game changes and it turns
around. But things go down a lot faster
than they go up. And and Bitcoin went up
pretty fast, you know, so it could go
down a lot faster as the air comes out
of the bubble and everybody is rushing
to salvage what they've got before it's
nothing, right? So that that will
eventually happen. There'll be a rush
for the exit. Give us a price prediction
for Bitcoin then before it goes to
nothing. If I could tell you that if I
knew how high Bitcoin was going to go, I
would buy it, right? If I knew. Well, I
remember I asked and then I would sell
it when it got to that price. I remember
I asked you this question a couple years
ago. I said, "Look, if I were to tell
you with certainty, I mean, maybe I'm a
time traveler, whatever, that Bitcoin is
going to 100K. Eventually, it did. Would
you buy back then?" I think the Brown
was at the time it was maybe less than
20K when you and I spoke about this and
you still said no. 100K worth of nothing
is still nothing. No. No. I wouldn't
have said I mean I would probably
wouldn't have believed you were a time
traveler. Sure. But but but assuming you
could convince me that you were in fact
a time traveler, right? And I and I knew
for a fact that Bitcoin was going to hit
100,000, of course, I would buy it at
20,000. In fact, if you were a time
traveler today and you told me that
Bitcoin was going to hit a million.
You'd have to tell me by when. Yeah. And
also, you'd have to tell me how much is
a cup of coffee going to cost. I want to
know like, you know, cuz you know, if
there's hyperinflation, I I could lose
money on a million dollar Bitcoin. It
might not it might not keep up. But if
you gave me the the facts, yeah, sure,
of course. But the reason I can't buy
Bitcoin is because I have no idea when
this bubble's going to pop. See, it's
easy to buy it if you believe in it. If
you don't think it's a bubble, well,
sure, just buy it. But if you know it's
a bubble, it's much harder to say, you
know, cuz people tell me, well, you
know, yes, it's a bubble and people are
dumb enough to buy it, and they're
probably going to keep buying it, and
it's going to go even higher. So why
don't you just buy it now to make money
off of all these idiots who keep buying
Bitcoin? And the problem is I don't know
when the idiots are going to stop
buying. And every time I would not have
the conviction to like ride it down
because I'd be afraid that it's going to
keep falling. So you have to you have to
you have to completely believe in it to
be able to ride it ride out the the
cycles. I I I don't believe in it,
right? I So how am I going to have any
kind of conviction? I'd be scared the
minute it went down. I wouldn't know
where the peak was. Um, and so I just I
just have nothing to do with it. But I
think at this point that people trying
to convince me that well maybe it's
going to go to 500,000, maybe it's going
to go to a million. All right, but it's
already 100,000. So a million is only
10x, which is not nothing, but I I own a
lot of stocks I think can go up 10x or
more. And so I'd rather gamble on those.
Yeah. Um, and I think there's a better
chance that Bitcoin goes down by 90%.
Than a lot of these I don't think the
stocks I'm buying are going to go down
that much. I mean, sure, yes, you know,
buying Bitcoin at a dollar, $5, $10,
$100 was a home run. By the way, you own
and a lot of gold stocks, okay? And a
lot of the minor that we spoke to, you
know, at this conference, their strategy
is to mine Bitcoin and hodddle it. Why
aren't gold companies mining gold and
hodling gold on the bench? Well, you
know, they a lot of them should be, I
guess. Do do you think that should be
the model? Well, you know, they got to
pay their workers. They got to pay, you
know, if they borrowed money, they got
to pay interest. So, they have a lot of
costs, right? Uh, but I actually think
what mining companies should be doing is
buying back their stock more than just
buying physical gold because I think in
most cases they're getting a better deal
on the gold by buying back their stock
because they're buying back their own
gold that they haven't mined yet. But to
the extent that gold companies, the big
companies now that have a lot of cash
now on the books, yes, they they they
they might as well hold gold instead of
all that cash. It would make more sense.
uh or they can pay dividends and the
shareholders can can buy buy physical
gold if if they want to but you know the
gold companies are in a business they
have a business you know the business is
mining and selling gold but they already
have tremendous gold in the ground so
they're not thinking of holding above
ground gold on top of the the gold that
they already they already have um but I
think you know gold stocks are are are
great bargains I mean most of them and
uh that's why I I I own so much and I I
recommend that people, you know, we
manage a gold fund, uh, the Europe
Pacific Gold Fund. We have, uh,
separately managed accounts. Uh, we're
managed portfolios of gold stocks. And I
think that for a speculative asset, and
I'm not, you know, saying that gold
stocks aren't speculative. I mean, it's
a very risky business mining gold. U,
but I think right now the riskreward is
tremendously in favor of buying these
stocks. Yes, you could lose money if I'm
wrong, but the amount of money you can
make, if I'm right, uh, dwarfs it, and
that's where I'd rather put risk capital
rather than gambling on more fools
bidding up Bitcoin. I'd rather just buy
these buy these mining stocks because
any money I were to put into Bitcoin, if
you say, "Hey, why don't you just throw
hundred grand a million dollars of
Bitcoin?" Okay, well, that's another 100
grand or a million that I can't invest
in gold mining stocks or something else.
And that's where I'd rather put my
chips. I just think I get better odds,
got more upside, I got less downside
because I don't believe, you know, is
Bitcoin going to go to $20 million or
these crazy numbers. I mean, to me, it
seems impossible other than through
hyperinflation, which, you know, renders
it, you know, meaningless. Yeah. uh but
in a in in real terms in purchasing
power terms and as as I mentioned you
know Bitcoin is lower by 10% priced in
gold than it was three years ago but
that's the time frame you picked what
about long term but that is a long term
as three years but what what about 10
years 20 well I think Bitcoin could be a
lot lower 20 years from now than it is
today 20 years ago no but how do we well
of course that's when it started right
yeah I mean look even if Bitcoin goes to
10,000, you could still go back to when
it started and say it's been the best
investment even though almost everybody
who owns it will be way down. And in
fact, even if Bitcoin goes to a
thousand, the return from a penny is
incredible, right? So, you can always go
back to the first Bitcoin and talk about
how it's the best performing asset. But
the problem is very few people owned it
then. I mean, even Michael strate
Michael Sailor with Strategy, his
average cost is about $70,000. for the
40 billion he's got in Bitcoin. I mean,
Bitcoin can easily go below $70,000. And
in fact, I think Micro Strategy, if they
had just bought gold instead of Bitcoin,
the returns would be about the same.
Except if he had bought gold, he could
actually sell it without crashing the
market. There's no way Strategy could
sell that Bitcoin at a gain. If he tried
to sell it, he'd end up losing money by
the time he sold uh the the last uh the
last Bitcoin he had. Um, so I just think
it's if you look back at the n at the at
the peak price from 2021, how do we know
that that's really not the peak? I mean,
we did get slightly above it uh after
Trump won for a day or two, but barely.
So, how do you know we don't have a
double top from 2021 and 2025? 202.
That's the double top. And maybe maybe
that's it. Maybe we're just distributing
all the Bitcoin uh from strong hands to
weak hands and uh it's going down. I
mean, if you're if you think that, you
know, we've peaked in the the NASDAQ, if
you think a lot of these tech stocks
have peaked, Bitcoin is going to go down
right along with them. I mean, it's high
highly correlated uh with that market. I
think we have time for one more
question, Bonnie. My last question is,
what has to happen for you to start
buying Bitcoin? Oh, I mean, I don't I
mean, I haven't bought it yet and it's
gone from practically nothing to a
100,000. So, if that hasn't convinced
me, right, what's going to convince me?
Think of a think of a scenario. Look, I
mean, it's well, you
know, when Bitcoin first like came onto
the scene when it, you know, all of a
sudden it was like $1,000, you know,
went up and people were like talking
about it. And this was like, what was
it, 2017 or earlier than that or 2013 or
what? I forget when it was
2014, but I remember a lot of companies
started coming out, we're going to take
Bitcoin. We're going to take Bitcoin.
There was a whole rush of companies that
said, we're accepting Bitcoin. And of
course, they were working with a company
called Bitay. And I was one of the first
people at Shift Gold to use Bitay where
you can, you know, take your Bitcoin and
use Bitay. They sell the Bitcoin, get
dollars, and then, you know, pay for the
gold, right? But a lot of companies
because all of a sudden people that had
Bitcoin had money and stores were like,
"Hey, I want people to spend that money
with me." And so they were currying
favor with the Bitcoin community by
saying, "Hey, you can take your Bitcoin
and and and we'll take it." And of
course, they weren't really taking
Bitcoin. They were taking dollars, but
they were partnering up with a company
that would that would make it easy to
sell your Bitcoin to get dollars to buy
their products.
Well, today fewer companies are actually
taking Bitcoin than than were back then.
Uh because they realize that nobody even
wanted to use their Bitcoin cuz it's we
don't want to use the hard money to
Well, you think it's hard money, but you
don't want to spend it because you think
it's going to go, but it's also very
expensive. The more people that try to
use Bitcoin, the more expensive it is to
use it. And so they say, "Hey, you know,
you can use your Bitcoin to buy a cup of
coffee." No, you can't because the
transaction costs are are higher than
the cup of coffee and by the time you
know the merchant gets your Bitcoin,
your coffee is cold, right? Because it
takes so long uh to pay for it. But on
the same token, right, I can tokenize
gold and you can buy a cup of coffee
instantly and cheaply and pay for it
with gold tokens. So, you know, gold
would work as a medium exchange. Wait,
going back to the question. So if more
merchants accepted Bitcoin, you would
buy it. Is that where you're going? I
you know, no, it's because no merchants
really accept it because they just work
with bitay. But look, I suppose what
everybody is saying is one day we're
going to wake up in hyper
bitcoinization. And bitcoin is going to
be money. There won't be any more
dollars or any more euros or any more
yen. That everywhere I go, the prices
are going to be in Bitcoin. Uh my, you
know, the insurance is going to be in
Bitcoin. you know, bonds are going to be
Bitcoin. Like, it's going to be a
Bitcoin world and Bitcoin is money. I
guess if I wake up in that world, I I'd
have to admit that I was wrong. Uh, and
that, you know, I just don't believe
that that's ever going to happen because
we're no closer to that now than we were
10 years ago. The only thing that's
changed about Bitcoin is more people are
gambling with it, right? So, you have
more people speculating in Bitcoin, but
they're not using it. And in fact, fewer
people are using it. They'll even
acknowledge that if you actually want to
use it, there are much better tokens.
Like if you want privacy, use Monero,
right? Bitcoin doesn't really give you
much privacy, but there are other
tokens. What people tell say now is
Bitcoin isn't for using, it's for
holding. Like they say it's like gold.
You don't do anything with it except
they forget that you do a lot with gold,
right? But they've reinvented Bitcoin as
digital gold because you can't use it
for anything else. So they pretend that
it's just like gold because gold has no
use. And some of the most foolish things
that I've ever heard said about gold are
from pe Bitcoiners, right? Uh because
they have to pretend that gold has no
value to ascribe value to Bitcoin
because they say, "Well, bit gold is
used for nothing, so it's okay for
Bitcoin to be used for nothing." Uh when
gold isn't used for nothing. And they
always say, "Well, there's so much gold.
There's asteroids around the world that
are made out of gold." You know, all
this nonsense. You know, and then you
know they just the just last week I
think there was news somebody was oh
they were able to turn lead into gold
with a
superconductor collider and they said
you see and I said yes you're right and
in a billion years of constant running
you can get one ounce who knows how much
that's going to cost in energy to to run
this collider for a billion years to get
an ounce of gold. Sure. This the earth
won't even be here by the time you get
that ounce. So money has to be scarce
and it has to be used to be valuable.
Bitcoin is scarce but it's not well
Bitcoin is scarce in a limited sense
that we have artificially imposed a
limit on the supply, right? Uh gold is
scarce by nature, right? I mean and so
it there's just a limited amount of it
in in the universe. Um but yes, you you
have to be scarce but you have to have
value. I mean, remember, money is the
most marketable commodity. Money
replaced barter. And and so what money
allows us to do is I don't have to have
a confluence of needs. A butcher doesn't
need to find a candlestick maker that
wants his meat, right? And the
candlestick maker doesn't need to find a
butcher who wants their candles, right?
They they trade gold. But if I'm a
butcher and the candlestick maker gives
me gold, I've received a valuable
commodity in exchange for for my meat.
I've exch I've got gold that can be made
into jewelry that can be used in
consumer electronics. I've got another
good, right? So I get if if I work and I
and my my employer pays me in gold, I
exchange my labor that has value and he
gave me gold that has value. But Bitcoin
has no value, right? So there is no real
transaction with Bitcoin on the other
side of it because Bitcoin hasn't given
you anything because Bitcoin isn't a
commodity that has value on its own. So
it's not money at best. Bitcoin is
currency which is a money substitute.
But what kind of currency is it? It's a
fiat currency. So it's a fiat digital
currency. It's the opposite of what the
Bitcoin community claims to be against.
Well, that was a great talk. Enjoy the
rest of your week at the world's largest
nothing conference. We'll look forward
to Bitcoin going to zero. Thanks, Beers.
Have a good All right, David. Thanks.
Thank you. All right.